hey guys this looks like a fun one we
have a semicircle and a quarter circle
inside of a square and it wants to know
what is the area of the square this is
part two in part one we found the length
of this segment right here if you want
to check out that video I'll put a link
up here and in the description and if
you want to try to find the area of this
Square pause it right now because I'm
going to solve it in 3 2 1 we have two
unknown values here I want to call those
X and Y since we know it's a square we
know that this 10 + x is equal to the 8
+ y and then we can subtract 8 from both
sides and we get Y is equal x + 2 this
looks important let's put a box around
it next let's focus on this radius right
here which we know is equal to 8 and
let's pivot it over here to this point
of tangency and we also know this radius
is equal to 5 and let's pivot it over
here to this point of tangency and then
let's complete this right triangle and
we can now do the Pythagorean theorem we
have the quantity x + 5^ 2 plus the
quantity y + 8 2 is equal 2 13 2 right
now we have two variables but in the
place of this y we can plug in x + 2 2 +
8 is equal to 10 so now we have x + 5^ 2
+ x + 10^ 2 this x + 5^ 2 means the same
thing as x + 5 * x + 5 and the x + 10 2
is the same thing as x + 10 * x + 10
after we multiply this out we get x^2 +
10 x + 25 and after we multiply this out
we get x^2 + 20x + 100 and then we can
add these together X2 + x is = 2x^2 10 x
+ 20x is = 30X and 25 + 100 is 125 and
that's all going to equal 13 s which is
169 nice since we have a quadratic we
want to set this whole thing equal to
zero so let's subtract 169 from both
sides the 2x^2 and the 30X can be copied
down 125 - 169 is equal to -44 and 169 -
169 is equal to 0 next let's divide
everything by two on the left hand side
2x2 / 2 is x^2 30X / 2 is 15x and -44 /
2 is -22 and then on the right hand side
0 / 2 is equal to 0 now there's a couple
different ways we can solve this but
let's do the quadratic formula it says x
equal to B + orus the < TK of B ^2 - 4 a
c whole thing over 2 a a is the 1 in
front of the x^2 B is the 15 in front of
the X and C is the constant -22 in the
place of both of these B's we can plug
in 15
in the place of both of these A's we can
plug in 1 and in the place of this C we
can plug in -22 152 is equal to 225 and
-4 * 1 * -22 is equal to POS 88 inside
the < TK 225 + 88 is equal to
313 and in the denominator 2 * 1 is
equal to 2 so this gives us a positive
value and a negative value and we know
that X is a positive length so we can
get rid of the negative value so X is
equal to -15 plus the < TK of 313 whole
thing ID 2 and we know that the side
length of the square is equal to x + 10
and in the place of the X we can plug in
all of this stuff in order to combine
these let's change this 10 into a 20
over2 we can combine this ne-15 over2
and this POS 20 over2 to give us POS 5
over2 and now we know the side length is
equal to 5 + the sarek of 313 / 2 and
that is approximately 11.3 and now we're
ready for our question the area of this
square is going to be this side length
squared we can multiply this times this
and that gives us an exact value of 169
+ 5un 313 everything over two and we
give that a label of square units and
the approximate value of this is 128.
7291 and this is the answer to our
question this is the area of this Square
let's put a box around it how exciting